They're two best friends, a million miles from home. On an incredible adventure,
beyond the boundaries of space and time. In a place called...
Mio in the Land of Faraway is a adventure, drama, fantasy
film directed by Vladimir Grammatikov.
Under the watch of his unkind realtives, lonely Bosse's luck is changed when
he is sent to the land where his real father is the King.
In that country, he sets out on a quest, together with his
new friend, to destroy the evil Knight Kato.
Mio / Bosse, played by Nick Pickard.
Jum-Jum / Benke, played by Christian Bale.
The King, played by Timothy Bottoms.
Kato, played by Christopher Lee.
The Weaver Woman, played by Susannah York.
The Swordmaker, played by Sverre Anker Ousdal.
Mio in the Land of Faraway (Swedish: Mio min Mio; Russian: Мио, мой Мио, romanized: Mio, moy Mio) is a 1987 fantasy film directed by
Vladimir Grammatikov, and starring Christopher Lee, Christian Bale, Nicholas Pickard, Timothy Bottoms and Susannah York.
Based on the 1954 novel Mio, My Son by Astrid Lindgren, it tells the story of a boy from Stockholm who
travels to an otherworldly fantasy realm and frees the land from an evil knight's oppression.
Mio in the Land of Faraway was co-produced by companies from Sweden, Norway and the Soviet Union with a budget of about fifty
million Swedish kronor, making it the most expensive film adaptation of an Astrid Lindgren book during her lifetime.
It featured an international cast consisting largely of British, Russian and Scandinavian
actors, while its filming locations included Stockholm, Moscow, Crimea, and Scotland.
The film was shot in English and subsequently dubbed in Swedish and Russian.
Its special effects were created by Derek Meddings.
The film's theme song, "Mio My Mio", was composed by two former ABBA members, Benny
Andersson and Björn Ulvaeus, and performed by the Swedish band Gemini.
Released in 1987, the film saw Nicholas Pickard's debut as an actor and
marked Christian Bale's first appearance in a feature film.
It won the Cinekid Film Award in Amsterdam, while its
theme song became a top three hit in Sweden.
In contrast, Swedish reviewers received the film unfavorably,
criticizing it as a poor adaptation of Lindgren's novel.
The film explores themes of friendship, prince, knight, orphan.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.